(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
今度はド・ド・ド・ド・歌いましょう。いいですか？
Let's sing "Do-Do-Do-Do" next. Are you ready?
この牧場で、お歌、歌ったりするんだー！
I'm going to sing songs on this ranch!
おんなじ景色見て歌えて、嬉しいー！
I'm so happy to be singing while seeing the same view as you!
歌が、好きなままでいられてよかった。
I'm glad I've been able to stay in love with singing.
君色ハナミズキ
Kimiiro Hanamizuki
作詞：角巻わため　作曲：柴山 太朗
Lyrics: Watame Tsunomaki / Music: Taro Shibayama
春の風に吹かれて
Blown by the spring breeze,
綿毛ふわり　横切っていく
Fluffy dandelion seeds drift past.
どこまで行くのかな
I wonder how far they'll go.
僕も辿り着けるかな
I wonder if I can reach there too.
ふと歩みを止めて
Suddenly stopping my pace,
振り返ってみる自分は
When I look back at myself,
どんな風に映ってる？
How do I appear to others?
純白のハナミズキ
Pure white dogwood flowers,
揺れる
Swaying.
ちょっと君に会いたい
I want to see you for a bit.
1分1秒　分かち合いたい
I want to share every minute and second with you.
優しいあの声今
That gentle voice, right now,
なんか聞きたく
Somehow, I've come to want
なったよ
to hear it.
夏の空は青くて
The summer sky is so blue,
打ち上げ花火　響き渡っていく
And fireworks echo throughout it.
どこまで届くのかな
I wonder how far they'll reach.
あの日 そっと...
That day, softly...
口ずさむメロディ
A melody hummed...
君は今何してる
What are you doing now?
どんなこと考えてるの
What kind of things are you thinking about?
気づくとまた思ってる
Before I know it, I'm thinking of you again
全力のハナミズキ 揺れる
The dogwood tree in full bloom sways
やっぱ君に会いたい
After all, I want to see you
1分1秒 分け合いたい
I want to share every minute and second with you
君のこと何でも
Everything about you...
色聞かせてほしい
I want to hear about its color
夜の帳に閉じ込め
Locked inside the veil of night
このキュンと赤く染まる
This heart-fluttering, turning bright red...
好きかも
...maybe I love you
ねぇ 君に会いたい
Hey, I want to see you
1分1秒 分け合いたい
I want to share every minute and second with you
僕のそばにはもう
By my side already...
君がいないと
...if you're not there
やっぱ君に会いたい
After all, I want to see you
1分1秒 駆け出したい
I want to run to you every minute and second
赤い実が弾けた
The red berries have burst open
今すぐ君のそばに行くよ
I'm going to your side right now
こんばんドドド～！
Kon-ban-dododo~!
ホロライブ4期生、角巻わためです！
Hololive 4th Gen's Tsunomaki Watame here!
みんな見に来てくれて、ありがとう、ありがとうございます！
Thank you everyone for coming to see me, thank you so much!
いや、「君色ハナミズキ」どうだったかな？
Well, how did you like "Kimiiro Hanamizuki"?
なんかこうやって3Dでね、みんなの前で歌うのは初めてなんですけど、どうでしたでしょうか？
It's my first time singing it in front of everyone in 3D like this, so how was it?
で、今日はね、「君色ハナミズキ」ということで、
And today, since it's "Kimiiro Hanamizuki",
ハナミズキをなんと作っていただきました！イエーイ！
they actually made dogwood trees for me! Yay!
見えるかな？
Can you see them?
おー、これは桜じゃないからね！ハナミズキですからね、これ！
Oh, these aren't cherry blossoms! They're dogwoods!
どこからどう見てもハナミズキ、純白のハナミズキですからね！
No matter how you look at it, they're dogwoods, pure white dogwoods!
しかもこれ、見て！これさ、ステージにさ、花びらがさ、当たるとさ...
And look at this! When the petals hit the stage...
うわぁ！
Whoa!
うわぁ！ピュン！チョンパ！
Whoa! Pyun! Chompa!
なんかちゃんとね、跳ね返ってね、どっか行くんだよ。あはは。
They actually bounce off and go somewhere. Haha.
これどっか消えてくんだよ、跳ね返って。一体どこに行くのかな？異世界なのかな？どうでもいっか！
They bounce and disappear. I wonder where they go? Another world? Oh well!
今日はね、「#角巻わため超絶生誕祭2022」というハッシュタグがありますので、
Today we have the hashtag #角巻わため超絶生誕祭2022, so...
ぜひ！ぜひぜひ、超絶ツイート、
please, please do some hyper-tweets!
みんなの面白い超絶ツイ、あ、面白くなくてもいいんだけど、
Everyone's funny hyper-tweets... well, they don't have to be funny,
超絶ツイートいっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱい、いっぱいしてください！今すぐしてください！
but please post lots and lots and lots of hyper-tweets! Do it right now!
Twitterやってない人は登録してください！お願いします！あはは。
If you don't use Twitter, please sign up! I'm counting on you! Haha.
では、みんな、たくさんスクリーンショットとかね、撮ったり、いっぱいの思いの丈をツイートしていただければ嬉しいなと思います。
So everyone, I'd be happy if you took lots of screenshots and tweeted all your feelings.
後で巡回しますからね！見ますからね！
I'll be checking them later! I'll be watching!
いや、とうとうやってきたよ。角巻わため、今日で...
Well, it's finally here. Today, Tsunomaki Watame is...
6歳です！イエイ！イエイ！イエイ！イエイ！あはは。
...6 years old! Yay! Yay! Yay! Yay! Haha.
今日で6歳、もうね、小学生だね、羊の小学校行かなきゃ。早く準備しなきゃ、ランドセル買わなきゃ。
I'm 6 today, so I'm an elementary schooler now. I have to go to sheep elementary school. Got to get ready, got to buy a backpack.
ね、まだまだ楽しみなこといっぱいありますが、このライブをまず楽しんでいってほしいなと思います。
There's still lots to look forward to, but first I want you to enjoy this live show.
ゲストさんもね、たくさん呼んでいるので...
I've invited lots of guests too...
お？この先、あ、ゲストパートだったかな？
Oh? After this... oh, was it the guest part?
あ、やべ、ちょっと待たせてるかもしれないな。多分ゲストさん準備してくれてると思うから、
Oh no, I might be keeping them waiting. The guests are probably getting ready,
ちょっと準備、わためも行ってくるわ！ちょっと待ってて！行ってくるわ！
so Watame is going to go get ready too! Wait just a bit! I'm off!
急げ、急げ！
Hurry, hurry!
あ、あ、急げ！
Ah, ah, hurry!
は、早くー！
Be quick!
忙しい忙しい。
Busy, busy.
それでも
Even so,
ヘミスフィア
作詞：岩里 祐穂　作曲：菅野 よう子
Hemisphere
Lyrics: Yuho Iwasato  Composition: Yoko Kanno
いったいこの僕に
what on earth can I
何ができるっていうんだ
be expected to do?
窮屈な
In order to change
箱庭の現実を
the cramped reality of this miniature garden,
変えるために
in order to change it,
何ができるの？
what can I do?
人生の半分も
I haven't even lived
僕はまだ生きてない
half of my life yet.
逆らって 抱き合って
Resisting, embracing each other,
無意識に刻まれてゆく 経験のタトゥー
a tattoo of experience is being unconsciously engraved.
崖っぷちに立たされた時
When I was standing on the edge of a cliff,
何かが僕の手を掴み
something grabbed my hand,
自分自身の在り処が 初めて見えたんだ
and I saw where I belonged for the first time.
もっと広いフィールドへ
To a wider field,
もっと深い大きなどこかへ
to somewhere deeper and larger,
よそ見もきかない世界へ
to a world where I can't look away,
向かってゆくだけ
I'll just keep heading there.
教えて
Tell me,
強さの定義
the definition of strength.
自分貫くことかな
Is it staying true to yourself?
それとも
Or is it
自分さえ捨ててまで
protecting what must be protected,
守るべきもの守ることですか
even if you have to throw yourself away?
砂の刃を風が
The wind kicks up
土煙をあげる
blades of sand and dust.
風の中あいつらは
In the wind, they
死ぬまで立ち続けなければいけないのさ
must keep standing until they die.
人は歩き続けてゆく
People keep on walking,
ただ生きてゆくために
just so that they can live.
不完全なベータを塗り替えながら進む
They move forward, overwriting incomplete data.
始まりの荒野 ひとりも
In the wilderness of the beginning,
歩き出してるらしい
one person seems to be starting to walk.
僕は灰になるまで 僕であり続けたい
I want to keep being myself until I turn to ash.
崖っぷちに立たされた時
When I was standing on the edge of a cliff,
何かが僕の手を掴み
something grabbed my hand,
自分自身の在り処が 初めて見えたんだ
and I saw where I belonged for the first time.
もっと広いフィールドへ
To a wider field,
もっと深い大きなどこかへ
to somewhere deeper and larger,
よそ見もきかない世界へ
to a world where I can't look away,
向かってゆくだけ
I'll just keep heading there.
流れに身を上げ
I'll give myself to the flow.
僕は僕のことが知りたい
I want to know about myself.
Mmm... mmm...
第六感
作詞：Reol　作曲：Giga / Reol
Sixth Sense
Lyrics: Reol  Composition: Giga / Reol
いつか見ていた映画の
Like the contents of a movie
中身みたい後日中
I saw once, several days later,
の駅前 空へ背伸びしてくビルディング
buildings are stretching towards the sky in front of the station.
昼が
The rhythm the day
鳴らすリズムと命の
plays and the sound of life
音がそろ
align together.
私はまだ未完成
I am still incomplete,
で不完全
and imperfect.
起死回生のハウトゥー
Knowing the how-to
知って
for a comeback.
うーーーあーーー
Ooooh, aaaah...
Yeah!
今が一番ヤバいのだろ かも かも かませ
Now is the most critical time, maybe, just let it loose.
今日は年甲斐ないことしたいの
Today, I want to do something reckless for my age.
Get up, it's night! だろ かも かも 教えて
Get up, it's night! Right? Maybe? Tell me.
物足りないの 引き合いたい
It's not enough, I want us to pull each other.
特大でぶっ放したい
I want to let it all out in a big way.
極上で謳歌したい
I want to enjoy it to the fullest.
さあ おいでませ アンドロメダ
Come, welcome to Andromeda.
I got it!
雨に連れ 夜をなぞり
Accompanied by rain, tracing the night.
I got it!
ごらん召しません この手だって
Won't you take a look? Even this hand...
弱さの悔いとかし賢さにあり
...lies in the regret of weakness and wisdom.
うーーー
Ooooh...
いつか話したよ
I told you once,
外とは違っているものさ
the outside is a different place.
そんな悲しまないでいいよ
You don't have to be so sad.
今が一番ヤバいのだろ かも かも かませ
Now is the most critical time, maybe, just let it loose.
走るはず嘘はつけない
I have to run, I can't lie.
Get up, it's night! だろ かも かも 教えて
Get up, it's night! Right? Maybe? Tell me.
速攻な 遊び合いたい
I want us to play together right away.
そこらへんのを 剥ぎ合いたい
I want us to strip away the ordinary.
特別をもっと感じたい
I want to feel something more special.
産声上げた日は わけもなく泣いていたのに
On the day I was born, I was crying for no reason,
今 僕ら 泣くことすら うまくできずに
but now, we can't even cry properly.
誰もしかもしれない 瞳も真似できない態度を
Maybe anyone can, but with an attitude and eyes that can't be imitated.
せーので手放せよ
Let it go on the count of three.
感覚でもねえよ
It's not even a sensation.
いつものそれ以外を
Everything other than the usual.
うーーーあーーー
Ooooh, aaaah...
Crazy, fantastic!
今が一番ヤバいのだろ かも かも かませ
Now is the most critical time, maybe, just let it loose.
今日は年甲斐ないことしたいの
Today, I want to do something reckless for my age.
Get up, it's night! だろ かも かも 教えて
Get up, it's night! Right? Maybe? Tell me.
教えて 教えて あーーー
Tell me, tell me, aaaah...
今最高潮なんですだろ かも かも かませ
It's at its peak right now, maybe, just let it loose.
このままどこまで行けるの
How far can we go like this?
後悔もないまま だろ かも かも 教えて
With no regrets, right? Maybe? Tell me.
もう 揺るがない この速度は
Already unwavering, this speed is...
独善とぶっ放したい
...something I want to let loose with self-righteousness.
はい！ということでね。あれ？
Alright! And so... wait.
カメラ、カメラどこかな？
Camera... where's the camera?
あれ？カメラさん？
Huh? Mr. Camera?
ちゃんと撮ってくれないと、困るよなー。
If you don't film me properly, I'll be in trouble.
ふふ、みんな何も見てないね？
Hehe, you didn't see anything, right?
誕生日だから許されるんだよ。
It's my birthday, so it's allowed.
わためは悪くないよねぇ！せーの！
Watame did nothing wrong! Ready, go!
一緒に！せーの！
Together! Ready, go!
わためは悪くないよねぇ！
Watame did nothing wrong!
イェーイ！
Yay!
ということで、
And so,
ぼたんちゃんと『ヘミソフィア』、
with Botan-chan, "Hemisphere,"
そして、一緒に歌ってみたかった、
and someone I've wanted to sing with,
おかゆ先輩、おかゆんと
Okayu-senpai, with Okayun,
『第六感』を歌って踊らせていただきました！
we sang and danced to "Sixth Sense"!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
大好きなぼたんちゃんと、あとおかゆんと
With my dear Botan-chan and Okayun,
一緒に歌ったり踊ったりできて最高にハッピーなんだー！
getting to sing and dance together makes me the happiest!
ダブルラリアット！
Double Lariat!
油断していただろう、みんな！
You were off your guard, weren't you, everyone!
いや〜、嬉しかったな。
Man, that was so much fun.
まあ、ぼたんちゃんはね、いつもコラボしてもらったりとか、
Well, with Botan-chan, we always collab,
こうやって、あの記念配信とかもね、毎回来てもらったりとかしてるんだけど、
and she comes to these anniversary streams every time,
おかゆは、結構わための配信でこうやって一緒にやるっていうのは、
but for Okayu, doing something like this on my stream
珍しいんじゃないかなと思います。
is quite rare, I think.
ね、おかゆの歌めっちゃ好きで、
See, I really love Okayu's singing,
『もぐもぐYUMMY！』とか、いろいろ、
like "Mogu Mogu YUMMY!" and stuff,
『デタバレネコ』とかね、いろいろ聴いてるんだけど、
and "Detabare Neko," I listen to all of them,
こうやって歌って、しかもね、ダンスまで一緒に踊ってもらえて、
and to sing like this, and even have her dance with me,
めちゃくちゃハッピー！どうだった？
I'm so happy! How was it?
かっこよかった？
Was it cool?
かっこよかった？どうだった？
Was it cool? How was it?
かっこよかった？
Was it cool?
嬉しい！
I'm so glad!
いや、まだね、実はゲストがおりまして、まだまだおりまして、
Actually, there are still more guests, more to come,
さっきの二人も、このあともまだ、
and the two from before will also be here later...
おっと、この先は言えないな。
Oops, I can't say any more.
では次は、めちゃくちゃ珍しいゲストだと思います。
Well then, I think the next one is a very rare guest.
...思います。
...I think.
多分ね、ほぼほぼコラボしたことないんじゃないかなと思いますよ。
I think I've almost never collaborated with them before.
いろんな方とね。
With various people, you see.
では、行きましょう！次のコラボ相手は...
Now, let's go! The next collaboration partner is...
こちら！
This person!
EYE
作詞・作曲：Kanaria
Lyrics/Composition: Kanaria
逸中の瞬き ほてりだす
A choice blink, and I start to flush
左に奉ずる 三等に スパイスでね
Offering to the left, in third class, with spice
痛いな この手に 腐りだす
It hurts, in these hands, it starts to rot
左に奉じて 狂ったように 罪入るでね
Offering to the left, I fall into sin as if mad
林道 林道 愛を重ねて
Gentian, Gentian, piling up love
林道 林道 耳飾り
Gentian, Gentian, an earring
林道 林道 いっそ隠して
Gentian, Gentian, just hide it already
林道 林道 きっとバラバララララ
Gentian, Gentian, surely in pieces
爛爛爛 故に EYE EYE
Brilliant, brilliant, therefore EYE EYE
故に 幕を引け 引っ張れ バラバララララ
Therefore, draw the curtain, pull it, in pieces
爛爛爛 故に EYE EYE
Brilliant, brilliant, therefore EYE EYE
既に そこを知れば 悪鬼 バラバララララ
If you already know that place, an evil spirit, in pieces
爛爛爛 ああ
Brilliant, brilliant, ah
穿つこの目で 絶えずその手で
With these piercing eyes, with those hands constantly
瞬きですら惜しいから
Because even a blink would be a waste
見えぬ姿で あらぬ素振りで
With an invisible form, with a feigned manner
放つ言葉で 溢れて
Overflowing with the words released
林道 林道 愛を重ねて
Gentian, Gentian, piling up love
林道 林道 耳触り
Gentian, Gentian, jarring to the ears
林道 林道 いっそ隠して
Gentian, Gentian, just hide it already
林道 林道 きっとバラバララララ
Gentian, Gentian, surely in pieces
爛爛爛 故に EYE EYE
Brilliant, brilliant, therefore EYE EYE
故に 幕を引け 一つ バラバララララ
Therefore, draw the curtain, just one, in pieces
爛爛爛 故に EYE EYE
Brilliant, brilliant, therefore EYE EYE
既に そこ知れば 悪鬼 バラバララララ
If you already know that place, an evil spirit, in pieces
独りぼっちだ ひどく甘美だ
All alone, it's terribly sweet
なぜ？
Why?
誰が待ってる ああ
Who is waiting? Ah
わあ、EYEかっこよかったなあ。
Wow, EYE was so cool.
あれ？
Huh?
あれ？さっきまで誰かと一緒に歌ってたような気がするんだけど、
Huh? I feel like I was singing with someone until just now.
黒っぽい、黒っぽい狐っぽい人と歌ってたような気がするんだけど...
I feel like I was singing with a dark, dark fox-like person...
狐なのか人なのかちょっとよくわかんないけど。あれ？みんな...
I'm not sure if it was a fox or a person. Huh? Everyone...
あれ？わためんだけ見えてた？
Huh? Only I could see them?
え、そうなの？わためんだけ見えてたの？
Eh, really? Only I could see them?
あれ、おかしいな。あれ？
That's strange. Huh?
しかもなんか誰かと似てたんだよなあ。似てたんだよなあ、誰かと。
And they looked like someone. They really did look like someone.
誰かと、なんか誰か来そうな気がするんだけど。あれ？
Someone... I feel like someone is about to come. Huh?
なんかチラチラ見られてる気がする。
I feel like I'm being peeked at.
あれ？
Huh?
誰かといたんだい？
Were you with someone?
さっきのフブちゃんのね、黒っぽい...
Earlier, Fubuki-chan's... dark...
えー、フブちゃん？え、白上なんも聞いてないよ。
Eh, Fubuki-chan? Eh, Shirakami hasn't heard anything.
フブちゃん分身したの？
Fubuki-chan, did you split yourself?
分身してないはず... あれ、おかしいな。
I shouldn't have... That's strange.
色違いだった？
Was it a different color?
色違い。
Different color.
イェーイ！バカタレサーカス！
Yay! Bakatare Circus!
自己紹介しなきゃ！
We have to introduce ourselves!
ほら、バカタレども並んで、バカタレども一緒にほら、3人で。
Look, Bakatare guys line up, the three of you together.
いらっしゃいませー。今日はねー、今日はバカタレサーカスの日なのだ！
Welcome! Today is Bakatare Circus day!
え、誰？名前、忘れてた。
Eh, who? I forgot your names.
誰？誰？誰？もう記憶なくなっちゃった。
Who? Who? Who? I've lost my memory already.
記憶なくなっちゃったの、わため。
You lost your memory, Watame.
はい、じゃあ。白上フブキと！
Okay then. I'm Shirakami Fubuki and!
不知火フレアと！
I'm Shiranui Flare and!
尾丸ポルカだよ！お前ら！
I'm Omaru Polka! You guys!
やれよ！ちゃんとやって！サーカスなんだよ！
Do it! Do it properly! It's a circus!
サーカスやって！サーカスやって！
Do the circus! Do the circus!
サーカスやって！どういうこと？やんないよ。
Do the circus! What do you mean? I won't.
やんないの？プレゼントにやって、今日何の日か知ってんの？
You won't? Do it as a present. Do you know what day it is today?
え、今日何の日だっけ？今日何の日だったっけ？
Eh, what day was it today? What day was it today?
こっちも記憶喪失だ。何だろうな。何でわからへんのや。
I have amnesia too. What could it be? Why don't you understand?
わため、教えて。今日は何の日？ヒントは？
Watame, tell us. What day is today? Any hints?
今日は、あの、おた、おた、おた...
Today is, um, Bir... Bir... Bir...
お多福？おたまじゃくし？違うよ！
Otafuku? Tadpole? No!
Happy Birthday to you
Happy Birthday dear Watame
おめでとー！嬉しい！
Congratulations! I'm so happy!
何歳になったんだい？
How old have you become?
６歳！６歳！６歳！
Six! Six! Six!
似合ったね６歳！
Being six suits you!
ランドセル買わなきゃね！
We have to buy you a backpack!
ランドセル買って！
Buy me a backpack!
何色にしようかな？
I wonder what color we should get?
何色が似合う？
What color would suit you?
青？赤？ピンクとか？
Blue? Red? Or maybe pink?
６年生になったら絶対ピンクはダメだと思うんで...
I think pink is definitely a no-go for a 6th grader...
茶色とかにしようよ！絶対ピンクはダサいってなると思うんで。
Let's go with brown! I'm sure she'll think pink is uncool.
あ、確かにね！恥ずかしくなっちゃうかも。
Ah, that's true! She might get embarrassed.
オシャレだね、茶色！
Brown is stylish, isn't it?
ランドセルつけてもらおうかね、じゃあ後でね。
Let's have her wear the backpack later then.
やばい、嬉しくなってきたな！嬉しい！
Oh man, I'm starting to get excited! I'm so happy!
我々、お祝いに来ただけなんで、そろそろ帰ろうか？
We just came here to celebrate, so shall we head home now?
いやいやいや！バイバイ！またね！
No, no, no! Bye-bye! See ya!
ちょっと待って！おいしょ、おいしょ...
Wait a minute! Heave-ho, heave-ho...
せっかく来たならさ、ちょっと見てごらんなさい、ここ！
Since you've come all this way, take a look at this!
お、どこですかここ？
Oh, where is this?
うわぁ、すげぇ！
Whoa, amazing!
ほら、みんな待ってるよ！
Look, everyone is waiting!
本当だ、みんな振って待っててくれてる！
It's true, everyone is waving and waiting for us!
そうだよ！ペンライト振ってるよ！
That's right! They're waving their penlights!
あそこの小さい子、あ、いいな、可愛い！
That little kid over there, oh, how nice, so cute!
あそこの緑のお姉さんもすごい素敵！
That lady in green over there is also wonderful!
ロリ？ロリかな？ロリもいる！
A loli? Is that a loli? There's a loli too!
危ない、危ない！押し合わないでください！
Careful, careful! Please don't push each other!
ロリっ子危ないよ！踏んじゃうから！
It's dangerous for the little ones! You might step on them!
ダメだよ、ダメダメ！
No, no! That's not good!
いや、あれやろうよ！
No, let's do that!
あれ？バンドがやりてぇんだよ！
Wait? I want to do a band!
エンジンやっていいっすか？
Can we get fired up?
バンドやりたいんだよ！見たい、いいね！
I want to do a band! I want to see that, sounds good!
楽器ないの、でも。楽器確かにないね。
But we don't have instruments. You're right, we don't.
どうしようか？何やりたい？
What should we do? What do you want to play?
自分はギターがいいな。
I'd like to play the guitar.
え、じゃあ花形じゃん！やりたいな。
Oh, so the star role then! I want to do that.
でもこの４人でしょ？わためはやっぱボーカルでしょ。
But it's just the four of us, right? Watame should be the vocalist, obviously.
ドラム？ドラム？
Drums? Drums?
でもドラム流石にないよな...
But there's no way there are drums here...
この辺とかにさ、ドラムあったらいいんだけどな...
It would be great if there were some drums around here...
出ないかな？ないかな？
Won't they come out? Maybe not?
あ！出てきた！あら！
Ah! They appeared! Oh my!
え、マジっすか？そんなドラム弾けないけど弾いちゃってもいいですか？
Ehh, are you serious? I can't really play the drums, but is it okay if I try?
いいよ、いいよ！スティック持ってる！
Go ahead! She's holding sticks!
ポル様も、ポル様も、なんかDJみたいなのやりたい、そしたら。
Pol-sama also wants to do something like a DJ then.
どの辺？どの辺？
Where? Where?
DJポルポロ、なんかここら辺、だってもういるじゃん、ここに！
DJ Pol-Poro... right around here, I mean, I'm already here!
ここにドーンって来たらさ、それかっこいいじゃん、なんか。流石にな...
If it came right here with a bang, that would be cool. But there's no way...
あ！出た！すげぇ！
Ah! It appeared! Amazing!
すげぇ、出とるやんけ！あるじゃん、何でも出るよ！
Wow, it's actually there! It's here, anything will appear!
すげぇこれ。マジかよ、すご。え、じゃあ自分もじゃあギターギター欲しいな。
This is incredible. Are you kidding me? Wow. Well then, I want a guitar too.
ギターギター。じゃあーん！
A guitar, a guitar. Ta-da!
あ、出た！出た！また来た！
Ah, it appeared! It's here! Another one came!
うわ、また来たよ！上から来た！上から来た！
Whoa, another one! It came from above! From above!
すげぇ！
Amazing!
ね、わためここにマイクあるよ！
Hey, Watame, there's a microphone here!
え、マイクある？本当だ、マイクもある！
Eh, there's a mic? It's true, there's a mic too!
じゃあ、わためボーカルでマイク！
Then, Watame on vocals with the mic!
ま、わため消去法でマイクだ、ボーカルだ。そうだね、消去法でボーカルの人が。
Well, by process of elimination, Watame's on the mic, she's the vocalist. Right, you're the vocalist by default.
そういうことですよ！わためマイク！
That's how it is! Watame on the mic!
いいじゃん、これでじゃあバンドができるね！
Nice, now we can form a band!
ね、練習しよ！練習してよ、やってみて！
Hey, let's practice! Practice, give it a go!
じゃ、叩くよ！じゃ、叩いて！チューニング変えるの？
Then, I'm gonna play! Okay, play! Are you changing the tuning?
じゃ、叩いて、叩いてみてよ！
Okay, play it, try playing it!
あ、ちゃんと鳴ってる！あ、ちょっと動いてんだよね！
Ah, it's actually making sound! Oh, they're moving a bit!
聞こえるかな？ドンドン、ドンドン。最高や、それ！鳴ってる鳴ってる！
Can you hear it? Boom boom, boom boom. That's the best! It's making sound!
なんかドラムらしからぬ音してますが... まだゲーム大会してる人がいる。
It sounds a bit unlike drums, though... There's someone still in a gaming tournament.
太鼓の達人やってる人いらっしゃいますけど。
We have someone here playing Taiko no Tatsujin.
おお！すごい、すごい！いいよ、いいよ、いいよ！
Oh! Amazing, amazing! Good, good, good!
や、任せてくださいよ！それっぽく叩くんで！
Hey, leave it to me! I'll play it convincingly!
それっぽく？それっぽく？ガチなんだ、なんか。
Convincingly? Convincingly? She's serious, somehow.
ガチっすよ！ガチで！じゃあDJやってよ、ガチなんだよ！
I'm serious! For real! Then you do the DJing, we're being serious here!
わための誕生日だもん、みんなさ！確かに、じゃガチDJやってよ！
It's Watame's birthday, everyone! True, then do some serious DJing!
やってよ、ガチで！どこまで？お前が振ったんだぞ！
Do it, for real! How far? You're the one who brought it up!
さあ行くわよ、全力ガチなのね、スクラッチ！
Here I go, full-on serious mode, scratching!
いいよいいよ、もっと激しくな！もっと激しく！
Good, good! Even more intense! More intense!
まだ電源通ってないんだよ！電源まだ入ってないから！
The power isn't connected yet! It's not turned on yet!
ねえ、まだ電源入ってないから。どこに？そうだね。
Hey, the power isn't on yet. Where is it? True.
ごめんごめん、いいよいいよ。じゃギター！
Sorry, sorry, it's fine. Now, guitar!
そう、ギターとかかっこいいやつね、ええねえ。
Yeah, some cool guitar stuff, sounds good.
なんかラーメン、ラーメンできそう。
It kind of makes me think of ramen.
ラーメンできそう。ラーメンできそうになっちゃったけども。
I feel like making ramen now. It sounds like ramen.
や、でも本気は本気でやろうかなと、じゃあ。
Well, then, I'm going to do this seriously.
集大成に思いますのでね。
Since I think of this as a culmination of everything.
じゃかじゃかじゃん。バンドお願いしてもいいですか？
Tada! Band, could you please start?
任せろーい！
Leave it to me!
もっとかっこいいのやりたいの！
I want to do something even cooler!
もっとかっこいいの！もっとかっこいいの！
Something cooler! Much cooler!
そういう感じなのかな、どうなんだろうね。
I wonder if that's how it'll feel. Who knows?
せーの、次の曲、なんだろうね。
Ready? What will the next song be?
なんだろうね。なんだろうね。
I wonder what it is. I wonder.
じゃあ準備してきますわ、あれね。
Well, I'll go and get ready for that.
はいはい。練習しようかね。
Yes, yes. Shall we practice?
ね、じゃあちょっと改めてチューニングしに、じゃあ。
So, I'll go and tune up again.
踊ろうかな。
Maybe I'll dance.
練習するにゃー！練習するにゃー！
Gonna practice! Gonna practice!
おまぽるちゃん！行くよ！
Omapol-chan! Let's go!
おまぽるちゃん！おいで！おいで！
Omapol-chan! Come here! Come here!
行くよ！おまぽるちゃん！
Let's go, Omapol-chan!
待ってください！座ってください！
Please wait! Please sit down!
play the world! feat. PABLO / 作詞：LiSA/田淵 智也 / 作曲：PABLO a.k.a. WTF!?
play the world! feat. PABLO / Lyrics: LiSA, Tomoya Tabuchi / Composition: PABLO a.k.a. WTF!?
sing it your eyes 合図響いた
sing it your eyes, the signal sounded
play the world! つまり連勝確定
play the world! that's a guaranteed win streak
play the world! 受けて立つ余裕じゃん
play the world! I've got the leeway to face it
play the world! かなり興奮してる
play the world! I'm pretty excited
let's play the world!
sing it your eyes 合図響いた
sing it your eyes, the signal sounded
play the world! つまり連勝確定
play the world! that's a guaranteed win streak
play the world! 胸にキック　突き刺し
play the world! pierce through with a kick to the chest
play the world! これが自由の入り口
play the world! this is the gateway to freedom
叫べ my name is YEAH! YEAH!
Shout out my name is YEAH! YEAH!
自由自在に Follow me YEAH! YEAH!
Freely and easily, follow me YEAH! YEAH!
後悔はさせない YEAH! YEAH!
I won't let you regret it YEAH! YEAH!
my name is my name is YEAH!
人生は続編へ yeah スピンオフなんかじゃないぜ
Life goes on to a sequel, yeah, it's not some spin-off
カットアウト？ナンセンス play the world!
Cut out? Nonsense, play the world!
繋がりグルーヴして go around
Connect and groove, go around
全部大切　捨てられるか！
Everything's precious, how can I throw it away!
目に目　声に声　愛に愛　基本中の基本
Eye for an eye, voice for a voice, love for love, the basics of basics
分かってろ！今から厳密に
Know this! From now on, precisely
play the world! 目をそらすなよ OK
play the world! don't look away, OK
叫べ my name is!! 最高だって信じたい
Shout out my name is!! I want to believe it's the best
産まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since I was born into this, until the very end
beat me beat me そうだよな
beat me beat me, that's right
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Enjoy this world to the fullest
愛し抜くと決めたよ　そして愛される覚悟も
I've decided to love it all, and I've prepared myself to be loved
決めたんだ
too.
これが僕だ　止まれない
This is me, I can't stop
つまり自由の入り口
which means the gateway to freedom
叫べ my name is!!
Shout out my name is!!
give and take? haha
100倍にして返すよ play the world!
I'll pay you back a hundredfold, play the world!
感謝感激も不要じゃない？
Isn't even gratitude unnecessary?
それよりも革命を見ようじゃない
Instead, let's look for a revolution
I can say... YEAH! YEAH! YEAH!
嫌味って何味？
What does sarcasm taste like?
知らなくてもいいや　関係ないし
I don't need to know, it doesn't matter anyway
噛み砕いて飲み干せば
If you chew it up and swallow it down
ほら歌になる
look, it becomes a song
最高を味わいたい
I want to taste the best
いつも同じじゃつまらないぜ
It's boring if it's always the same
beat me beat me そうだよな
beat me beat me, that's right
ほら希望が有り余ってる
look, there's hope to spare
変幻自在に迫る
Approaching ever-changingly
光の色した高揚の sweet spot
the sweet spot of light-colored exaltation
ワクワクが止まらない
The excitement won't stop
つまり自由の入り口
meaning the gateway to freedom
産まれ変わることを恐れない
I'm not afraid of being reborn
失くしたって進むしかない
Even if I lose it, I have no choice but to go forward
生き続けろ絶対何がなんでも
Keep on living, no matter what
そうだろう！
Don't you agree!
運命はいつも僕の
Fate is always just ahead of me
先でそっと手招いてるんだ
beckoning to me softly
諦めるな逃げるな
Don't give up, don't run away
これが gateway to freedom
this is the gateway to freedom
OH YEAH...
最高だって信じたい
I want to believe it's the best
産まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since I was born into this, until the very end
beat me beat me そうだよな
beat me beat me, that's right
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Enjoy this world to the fullest
続編を始めよう
Let's start the sequel
自由奔放三昧 my name is
Self-indulgent and free-spirited, my name is
最高だって信じたい
I want to believe it's the best
生まれ落ちたからには最後まで
Since I was born, until the very end
beat me beat me そうだよな
beat me beat me, that's right
この世界を遊び尽くせ
Enjoy this world to the fullest
愛し抜くと決めたよ
I've decided to love to the end
そして愛される覚悟も決めたんだ
And I've also prepared myself to be loved
これが僕だ止まれない
This is me, I can't stop
つまり自由の入り口
In other words, the entrance to freedom
叫べ my name is
Shout it out, my name is
あぁ、いつものように過ぎる日々に欠伸が出る
Ah, I yawn at the days passing by as usual
さんざめく夜、越え、今日も渋谷の街に朝が降る
Crossing the noisy night, morning falls on the city of Shibuya again today
どこか虚しいようなそんな気持ち つまらないな
A somewhat empty feeling like this is boring
でもそれでいい そんなもんさ これでいい
But that's okay, that's just how it is, this is fine
知らず知らず隠してた本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let the true voice you've been hiding unconsciously resonate, see
見ないふりしていても確かにそこに ある
Even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely there
感じたままに描く 自分で選んだその色で
Paint it as you feel, with the colors you chose yourself
眠い空気纏う朝に 訪れた青い世界
In the morning wrapped in sleepy air, the blue world has arrived
好きなものを好きだと言う 怖くて仕方ないけど
To say you like what you like, I can't help but be scared
本当の自分 出会えた気がしたんだ
I felt like I was able to meet my true self
あぁ、手を伸ばせば伸ばすほどに 遠くへ行く
Ah, the more I reach out, the further it goes
思うようにいかない今日も また慌ただしくもがいてる
Today, things aren't going as expected, and I'm struggling hectically again
悔しい気持ちも ただ情けなくて 涙が出る
The feeling of regret is just pathetic, and tears come out
踏み込むほど 苦しくなる 痛くもなる
The more I step in, the more painful and distressing it becomes
感じたままに進む 自分で選んだこの道を
Go on as you feel, along this path you chose yourself
重いまぶた擦る夜に しがみついた青い誓い
In the night when I rub my heavy eyelids, I clung to the blue oath
好きなことを続けること それは楽しいだけじゃない
Continuing to do what you love isn't just about having fun
本当にできる？ 不安になるけど
Can I really do it? I get anxious, but...
何枚でも ほら何枚でも 自信がないから描いてきたんだよ
No matter how many sheets, see, no matter how many, I've been drawing because I have no confidence
何回でも ほら何回でも 積み上げてきたことが武器になる
No matter how many times, see, no matter how many, what I've accumulated will become a weapon
周りを見たって 誰と比べたって 僕にしかできないことはなんだ
Even if I look around or compare myself to anyone, what is the thing only I can do?
今でも自信なんかない それでも
I still don't have any confidence, but even so...
感じたことない気持ち 知らずにいた想い あの日踏み出して
Feelings I've never felt, thoughts I didn't know I had, stepping out that day...
初めて感じた この痛みも全部
Even this pain I felt for the first time, all of it...
好きなものと向き合うことで 触れたまだ小さな光
By facing what I like, I touched a still small light
大丈夫、行こう あとは楽しむだけだ
It's okay, let's go, all that's left is to enjoy
全てをかけて描く 自分にしか出せない色で
Paint with everything I have, in colors that only I can produce
朝も夜も走り続け 見つけ出した青い光
Continuing to run morning and night, I found the blue light
好きなものと向き合うこと 今だって怖いことだけど
Facing what you like is still a scary thing even now, but...
もう今はあの日の 透明な僕じゃない
I'm no longer the transparent me of that day
ありのままの かけがえのない僕だ
I'm the irreplaceable me, just as I am
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let the true voice you've been hiding unconsciously resonate, see
見ないふりしていても 確かにそこに 今もそこにあるよ
Even if you pretend not to see it, it's definitely there, it's still there now
知らず知らず隠してた 本当の声を響かせてよ、ほら
Let the true voice you've been hiding unconsciously resonate, see
...見せてよ
...show me.
さあ、見ないふりしていても
Now, even if you pretend not to see,
確かにそこに 君の中に
it's certainly there, inside of you.
うわあ！『RAISE THE WORLD』と『群青』、楽しかったなあ！
Wow! "RAISE THE WORLD" and "Gunjou" were so much fun!
みんなも楽しかったですか？カッコよかった？
Did you guys enjoy it too? Was I cool?
お？切ない気持ちになった？
Oh? Did you feel a bit sentimental?
ふんふんふん...
I see, I see...
いや、みんなコメント見えてますからね。
I can see all your comments, you know.
ありがとう！楽しんでもらえたようで嬉しい！
Thank you! I'm glad you enjoyed it!
ま、こんなところでちょっとみんなにお伝えしたい...
Well, on that note, there's something I'd like to tell you all...
...あ、こ、こ、と、とこ、こと...ことがあるんだけど...
...ah, th-th-th-thing... there's something...
噛んじゃった。
I bit my tongue.
え、ちょっとだけ告知をさせていただいてもいいでしょうかー？
Um, may I make a quick announcement?
いいよ！ありがとー！
Okay! Thank you!
では、行きます！えー、まず１！
Here we go! First, number one!
角巻わため超絶生誕グッズ、この後発売になります！販売開始！
Tsunomaki Watame Hyper Birthday Goods will be on sale after this! Sales start!
いぇいいぇいいぇいいぇいいぇい！
Yay yay yay yay yay!
内容は？お？
What are the items? Oh?
ラバーマットと、マフラーと、スリッパ！
A rubber mat, a muffler, and slippers!
の三点で、全部セットを買っていただいた方には...
Those three items. For those who purchase the full set...
直筆サイン入りポストカードと特典ボイスがつきます！
you'll get a hand-signed postcard and a special voice track!
いぇいいぇいいぇいいぇいいぇい！
Yay yay yay yay yay!
え、毎年のことではあるんですけど、
Um, as I do every year,
え、サインは全部書かせていただきます！
I'll be signing all of them myself!
数量限定ではございません。
It's not a limited quantity item.
なので、みんな争わずにね、ゆっくり買ってくださいね。
So please, everyone, buy them at your own pace without fighting over them.
え、そして、何で今、これから夏なのに
And also, you might wonder why, even though summer is coming,
マフラー？スリッパ？何で何で何で？って思っている方もいらっしゃると思うんですが、
a muffler? Slippers? Why, why, why? I'm sure some of you are thinking that,
受注生産のため、みんなの元に届く期間がね、ちょっとかかってしまうので、
but because they're made-to-order, it takes a bit of time for them to reach you.
名探偵わためはそれを見越して、マフラーやスリッパを今作ったんですね。
Detective Watame anticipated that and made the muffler and slippers now.
これ賢い。賢い。賢いね。
That's smart. Smart. So smart, right?
そう、なので多分涼しくなってきた頃か、寒くなってきたなって頃に
Right, so they'll probably arrive around the time it gets cool or starts feeling cold,
マフラーとかスリッパとかね、届くと思いますので、今からどうでしょうか。あなたの首元に。
so how about getting one now for your neck?
これでね、一緒に冬を過ごせたら嬉しいなって思います。
I'd be happy if we could spend the winter together with this.
ラバーマットも、ふーみママがめっちゃ可愛く描いてくれたんですよ！
Also, Fuumi-mama drew the rubber mat so cutely!
なんとわためいとも一緒に、あの、描いてあるとか...
And Watame-mates are also, um, drawn there...
...ないとかあるとか...
...or not... or they are...
ま、いつも一緒だからね、わためとわためいとはね、んね。
Well, Watame and Watame-mates are always together, right? Yeah.
なので是非、あなたのおうちに置いてください。お願いします。
So please, do put it in your home. Please.
そして特典ボイスは特典なので買ってからのお楽しみです！よかったらみんな、どしどし買ってください！
The special voice is a bonus, so look forward to it after you buy it! Please feel free to buy them, everyone!
え、そして、２！
And then, number two!
昨年行った、角巻わためファーストソロライブ『わためぇナイトフィーバー!!』のブルーレイが、６月２９日に発売になります！
The Blu-ray of my first solo live "Watame Night Fever!!" held last year will be released on June 29th!
いぇーい！
Yay!
もうね、予約は開始してるんですけど、是非よかったら買ってみてください。よろしくお願いします。
Pre-orders have already started, so please check it out. Thank you.
ということで、告知パートはこれで一旦終わりだ。一旦ね。
With that, the announcement part is over for now. Just for now.
ちょっと次の曲、着替えてきてもいいですか？
May I go change for the next song?
そんな待たせないから大丈夫！そんな待たせない大丈夫！すぐ着替えるから大丈夫だよ！
I won't keep you waiting long, so it's okay! It's okay, I won't be long! I'll change quickly, so don't worry!
ほら、ズッポンポンポンポコポコポコポン...
Look, zupponponpon pokopokopokopon...
...今脱いで、脱いで、履いて、履いて、脱いで、履いて、脱いで、脱いで、よし。
...now taking it off, off, putting it on, on, off, on, off, off, alright.
テッテレーン！
Ta-da!
ソロライブの時に着させていただいたライブ衣装です！
This is the live outfit I wore during my solo live!
今日はこれを着て、初めて歌う歌をみんなに歌いたいと思います！
Today, wearing this, I'm going to sing a song for everyone that I've never sung before!
心を込めて歌いたいと思いますので、みんな心して聞いてください。
I'll sing it with all my heart, so please listen closely.
わためが作詞をして...
Watame wrote the lyrics...
My Songの
Shota Horie, who composed
曲を作ってくださった、堀江晶太さんが曲を書いてくれました！
"My Song," wrote this song too!
わための新しいオリジナルソング、
Watame's new original song,
『夢見る羊』
"Dreaming Sheep."
叶えたい未来へ
To the future I want to fulfill
心の準備OK?
Are your hearts ready?
さあ、一歩踏み出して
Now, take a step forward
いっせーの、せ！
Ready, set, go!
夢見る羊
作詞：角巻わため　作曲：堀江晶太
Dreaming Sheep
Lyrics: Tsunomaki Watame  Composition: Shota Horie
真っ白な羊に命が宿って
Life was breathed into a pure white sheep
目覚めたんだこの大きな世界で
And it woke up in this vast world
何をしようか　どこに行こうか
What should I do? Where should I go?
冒険は始まった
The adventure has begun
フラフラな足取りで弱々しく
With unsteady steps, so weakly
声も震えて上手く鳴けない
My voice trembled, and I couldn't bleat well
そんな自分がやるせない
I felt so helpless about myself
自信喪失気味です
I was feeling quite discouraged
でも時間は進む
But time goes on
気持ちばかり焦る
Only my feelings were in a rush
「ゆっくりでいいから泣いてちゃだめよ」
"It's okay to take it slow, so don't cry"
叶えたい未来へ
To the future I want to fulfill
心の準備OK?
Are your hearts ready?
さあ、一歩踏み出して
Now, take a step forward
1, 2, 3
僕は君と出会って　自信を取り戻して
I met you and regained my confidence
ゆっくりと今　確かに歩み出した
Slowly but surely, I've started walking now
夢を見つけて　いくつも抱きかかえて
Finding dreams and holding many of them close
君と話した　未来を掴みに行こう
Let's go grab the future we talked about
一緒に　隣歩いて行こう
Let's walk side by side together
まっすぐな羊に迷いはないのさ
There's no hesitation in this straightforward sheep
走り出したら急には止まれない
Once I start running, I can't stop suddenly
周りを巻き込む　そんな羊に今
To become such a sheep that draws others in
なれる気がしたんだ
I felt like I could do it now
明日を迎えたくない日も
Even on days when I don't want to face tomorrow
アンニュイな朝も昼も夜も
On listless mornings, afternoons, and nights
半分こして　食べ合って夢見よう
Let's share them half and half, and dream together
このまま　一緒に夜に溶けて
Let's just melt into the night together like this
君と出会って　自信を取り戻して
Meeting you and regaining my confidence
泥まみれでも　何度も走り出した
Even covered in mud, I ran again and again
夢を見つけて　いくつも抱きかかえて
Finding dreams and holding many of them close
君と話した　未来を掴みに行こう
Let's go grab the future we talked about
見たこともない...
Never seen before...
景色広がる世界へ　連れて行くよ
I'll take you to a world where the scenery unfolds
一緒に　ずっと歩いて行こう
Let's walk together forever
同じ未来へ
Toward the same future
水飲んでええか？
Can I drink some water?
ちょっと水飲んでもいいですか？
May I drink some water for a moment?
おー、みんな、どうだったかな？
Oh, everyone, how was it?
おー、ドキドキしたで。
Oh, my heart was racing.
はあー、生き返る。
Ah, I feel alive again.
あー、美味い。
Ah, that's refreshing.
はあー、ただいま。
Phew, I'm back.
今お披露目した『夢見る羊』ですが、
The song "Dreaming Sheep" that I just premiered...
なんと今日の24時から楽曲配信開始となります！イェーイ！
Will be available for digital distribution starting from midnight tonight! Yay!
角巻わため オリジナル曲「夢見る羊」
6/6(Mon) 24:00 release
Tsunomaki Watame Original Song "Dreaming Sheep"
作曲は、My Songの堀江晶太さん、えー、そして、
The composer is Shota Horie, who did "My Song," and...
作詞は、角巻わためさん...わため、私ですね。
The lyrics were written by Tsunomaki Watame... that's me.
『キミ色ハナミズキ』に続き、わためが書いてみました。
Following "Kimi-iro Hanamizuki," I tried writing them myself.
そして、この曲は、わためがホロライブに入ってデビューした時から、
And this song, since I joined Hololive and debuted,
順々にね...
Step by step...
今に至るまでの気持ちとかを、書かせていただいて、
I've written about my feelings up to this point,
わためいとのみんなとまだまだ先に進んでいくぞ！という気持ちをね、
and my feeling of "I'm going to keep moving forward with all of you Watamates!"
込めたそんな楽曲となっております。
That's the kind of song it is.
みんなテンション上げたい時とか、あとは、
When you want to get hyped, or...
いつ来るかわかんないんだけど、またライブとかね、やる前とか、
I don't know when it'll be, but before a live concert...
いや、やっぱエブリデイだね、毎日聞いてほしいなと思います！
Actually, every day! I want you to listen to it every day!
楽曲のリンクは概要欄に記載いたしますので、
The link to the song will be in the description,
本日の24時！24時となります！
so it will be out at 24:00 today! 24:00!
ぜひ！ぜひ楽曲購入よろしくお願いいたします！
Please! Please do buy the song!
そしてそして、「夢見る羊」のムービーが、この後！
And then, the music video for "Dreaming Sheep" will be...
投稿されます！イエーイ！
...posted after this! Yay!
いやもうね、振り付けがね、さっきも見てもらったと思うんだけど、
Man, the choreography, as you saw earlier...
めちゃくちゃ可愛くてね、素敵なんだよね。いつもお世話になってます、
...it's so cute and wonderful. I'm always grateful to...
HIROMI先生に振り付けをしていただきまして、
...HIROMI-sensei for the choreography.
頑張って踊ってみたりしたので、ぜひムービーの方もみんな、
I worked hard on the dancing, so everyone, please check out the MV too!
見てくれー！お願いします！
Please watch it!
わあ、いや、いや、終わりたくないなぁ。
Wow... Man... I don't want this to end.
もう、まだ終わんないけどな、まだ終わんないけど、終わりたくないなぁ。
It's not over yet, but I don't want it to end.
終わりたくない。あ、なんか、あ、ブレイクダンス始まっちゃう。
I don't want it to end. Oh, it's like... oh, the breakdancing is starting.
あ、やばい、ブレイクダンス始まっちゃう。
Oh no, the breakdancing is starting.
ちょっと、わためブレイクダンスなんてやったことないから無理やったわ。
Wait, Watame's never done breakdancing before, so that was impossible.
今日は、わための誕生日に最後まで付き合ってくれて、
Thank you so much for staying with me until the end...
本当にありがとうございました！
...on Watame's birthday!
まだ終わんないけどね！
Though it's not over yet!
そしていつも支えてくれている、スタジオのスタッフさーん！とか、
And to the studio staff who always support me!
運営さーん！とか、あとはわためいとのみんなー！とか、
And the management! And all the Watamates!
わためいとじゃなくてもホロライブを応援してくれてるみんながいるから、
And everyone else who supports Hololive even if you're not a Watamate.
この6才の誕生日を迎えられたと思っています。
It's because of you that I've reached this 6th birthday.
本当に、本当にありがとうございました、いつも。
Thank you so, so much for everything, always.
感謝してもしきれないくらいです。
I can't thank you enough.
まだまだ、これから先も7才、8才、9才、10才、11才、100才！
Still, from here on: 7th, 8th, 9th, 10th, 11th... 100th birthday!
もうどんどんね、活動を頑張っていきたいと思ってるので、
I want to keep working harder and harder on my activities,
みんなも応援よろしくお願いいたします！
so please keep supporting me!
ということで、まだね、これじゃ物足りないよね？
So, this isn't enough yet, right?
まだここで終わるなんて思ってる奴いねーよな？帰ってる奴いねーよな？
Nobody thinks it's over yet, right? Nobody's leaving, right?
点呼とりますよ。お。
I'm taking roll call. Oh.
わためいと1番さん、わためいと2番さん、3番さん、初めて番号で呼んだわ。
Watamate No. 1, Watamate No. 2, No. 3... That's the first time I've called you by numbers.
ごめんごめん、アドリブすみません。
Sorry, sorry, excuse the ad-lib.
じゃあね、この後、ま、わためのライブといえばアンコールだよね！
Well, after this, a Watame live concert means an encore!
ねー！今日来てくれたゲストさんたちも、みんな待っててくれてんじゃ、
Right! I bet all the guests who came today are waiting too,
ないのかなー。この後のアンコール見ないとみんな損しますのでね、
aren't they? You'll be missing out if you don't watch the encore,
ぜひ最後まで楽しんでってください！
so please enjoy it until the very end!
では、ステージ移動だー！
Now, let's move to the stage!
Chu chu yeah!
Be be be!
Without you!
ああ！なんてことだ　些細な過ちだ
Ah! What a thing, it's a minor mistake
自分のことに　タラタラッタ　ステップ
Doing my thing, tara-taratta step
どうして突然？　逃げ出したっていいでしょう
Why so suddenly? It's fine to run away, right?
だけど何だか　気まぐれモードになり
But somehow, I get into a whimsical mode
そんな気分になっちゃって
I ended up in that kind of mood
始まりはそんな風で
That's how it started
つまりはらしくないようで
In short, it's unlike me
でも今じゃ扉開けてほら
But now, open the door, look
声が聞こえるよ　さあ！
I can hear a voice, now!
行こう！
Let's go!
どこへでも！
Anywhere!
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ
I have the courage to become your wings
Please stay with me
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
I'm not afraid of any trial because I have that magic
Now and forever
初めて出会う世界に花束を贈ろう
Let's give a bouquet to this world we've met for the first time
Made in society
ただその瞬間を待つ守れるよ
I'll just wait for that moment, I can protect it
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーションでも別に構わない 明日から平和なら
It doesn't matter if our communication is awkward, as long as tomorrow is peaceful
Chu chu yeah!
Without you!
ああ、どうしてまた素直になれなくて
Ah, why is it that I can't be honest again?
自分のことで chu chu chu you feel?
With my own issues, chu chu chu, you feel?
リアルはそのままスピード上げていこう
Let's keep reality as it is and pick up the speed
だけどなんだか足止めモードになり
But for some reason, I've entered a standstill mode
いつかも思い出しちゃって 人に出て行っても嫌じゃない
I've started remembering things, it's not bad to go out among people
誰にも頼らなくてもいい
I don't have to depend on anyone
でも扉の向こう側が騒がしい
But it's so noisy on the other side of the door
声が聞きたいよ 今
I want to hear your voice now
行こう！
Let's go!
どこまでも！
Everywhere!
僕は君を背中に乗せて空を舞うよ
I'll carry you on my back and soar through the sky
Please stay with me
いつか心が離れても その時は笑ってて
Even if our hearts drift apart one day, please keep smiling then
Now and forever
守りたいこの世界に
In this world I want to protect
青空のラプソディ
Blue Sky Rhapsody
Make me happy
ただいつまでも奏でていてよ
Just keep playing it forever
でこぼこなコンビネーションでも別に大丈夫 明日はもっと平和になる
It doesn't matter if our combination is uneven, tomorrow will be even more peaceful
ほんの小さな傷を
Letting even the smallest wounds
太陽にさらして
Be exposed to the sun
分け合ったよ 君と
We shared them together
痛みは暑さの中に溶けていった
The pain melted away into the heat
Chu chu yeah!
右のビート弾く僕ら
As we strum the beat on the right
手を叩いて
Clap your hands
Chu chu yeah!
ブギなリズムで弾むチェリー
Cherries bouncing to a boogie rhythm
飛び跳ねてさあ
Come on, let's jump
右のビート弾く僕ら
As we strum the beat on the right
手を叩いて
Clap your hands
Chu chu yeah!
ブギなリズムで弾むアリーナ
The arena bouncing to a boogie rhythm
行くぞ！
Here we go!
どこまでも！
To everywhere!
僕は君の翼になれる勇気があるよ
I have the courage to become your wings
Please stay with me
どんな試練も怖くない その魔法があるから
I'm not afraid of any trial because I have that magic
Now and forever
君と出会い世界は
The world I met with you
花束に溢れた
Overflowed with bouquets
Make me happy
ただその瞬間を待つ守れたよ
I just waited for that moment, I could protect it
ちぐはぐなコミュニケーションでも別に構わない 明日が平和なら
It doesn't matter if our communication is awkward, as long as tomorrow is peaceful
Chu chu yeah!
Please be me
息を吐き出し
Letting out a breath
Without you!
角巻わため超絶誕生日記念グッズ
Tsunomaki Watame Super Birthday Commemorative Goods
この後21時から販売開始！
Sales start at 21:00 after this!
ラバーマット、マフラー、わためぇスリッパの三種類です。
There are three types: a rubber mat, a muffler, and Watamee slippers.
そして、フルセットを購入すると直筆サイン入りポストカードと特典ボイスがついてきまーす！
And if you buy the full set, it comes with a hand-signed postcard and bonus voice!
数量限定ではなく全てにサインとメッセージを書きますので、ぜひお買い求めください！
These aren't limited quantity; I'll sign and write messages on every single one, so please buy them!
そしてそして！角巻わため新オリジナル曲、「夢見る羊」！
And then, and then! Tsunomaki Watame's new original song, 'Dreaming Sheep'!
My Songを手掛けた堀江晶太さんに曲を書き下ろしていただき、わためが作詞をしました！
Shota Horie, who worked on 'My Song', composed the music, and I, Watame, wrote the lyrics!
この後24時から各種音楽配信サービスにて配信開始！
Distribution starts at 24:00 today on various music streaming services!
そしてそしてそして！この後、「夢見る羊」のムービーがわためちゃんねるで投稿されるので、ぜひ見てください！
And then, and then, and then! The music video for 'Dreaming Sheep' will be posted on my channel shortly, so please check it out!
さらに！この後すぐ21時30分、9時半からはメンバーシップ限定でライブのアフターパーティーをしますよー！
Furthermore! Right after this at 21:30 (9:30 PM), I'll be holding a members-only after-party for the live!
「夢見る羊」を聞きながら待機しててくださーい！それでは！
Please wait while listening to 'Dreaming Sheep'! See you then!
角巻わため超絶生誕祭 2022
Members only メンバー限定配信
Tsunomaki Watame Special Hyper Birthday 2022
Members only: Member-limited broadcast
はっ！
Ha!
グッズに
Merch,
夢見る羊のムービーに
the Dreaming Sheep movie,
メンバーシップ限定配信に
the membership-only stream,
レッツゴー！
and let's go!
角巻わため超絶生誕祭 2022
Tsunomaki Watame Special Hyper Birthday 2022